<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" 
      xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" 
      xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" 
      xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" 
      version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>Luke Morris</title>
<link>https://morrisLuke.github.io//blog.html</link>
<atom:link href="https://morrisLuke.github.io//blog.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<description>Healthcare Data Analytics | Data Science | R | Quarto</description>
<generator>quarto-0.9.301</generator>
<lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2022 07:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<item>
  <title>Not promising much, but here goes…</title>
  <link>https://morrisLuke.github.io//posts/not-promising-much-but-here-goes/post.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p>Ask anybody who has worked with me, they’ll tell you I’m the king of underpromising then overdelivering.</p>
<p>I’m hoping that turns out to be the case with this shiny new Quarto portfolio site and blog I built.<sup>1</sup></p>
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-right">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://morrisLuke.github.io//posts/not-promising-much-but-here-goes/images/hex_stickers.jpg" class="img-fluid figure-img" alt="The back of Luke's laptop, displaying sundry R hex stickers" width="1200"></p>
</figure>
</div>
<p>Here is what I’m hoping to accomplish:</p>
<p><strong>Watch one, do one, teach one:</strong> I’m cribbing this mentality from the talented nurses I spend my workday serving. I began learning R back in 2018 as part of my <a href="https://onlinedsa.merrimack.edu/business-analytics/">Business Analytics master’s program</a>. With a few years of experience under my belt, it’s time to pay forward what I learned from those a few steps ahead of me then.</p>
<p><strong>Get some healthcare example cases out there:</strong> Maybe I’m just looking in the wrong places, but it’s hard to find direct parallels to things I’m doing around the hospital online. That likely has to do with <a href="https://www.hipaa.com/">HIPAA hurdles</a>. But I’m going to start looking for some available mock hospital data and putting together some work with those to give people interested in a healthcare data career a taste of what they can expect. So if you know of any mock hospital data OK for blogging examples with, <a href="mailto:hey@lukesmorris.com">let me know</a>. Otherwise, I’ll be digging into <a href="https://github.com/ropensci/charlatan"><code>charlatan</code></a> to try my hand at creating my own fake dataset.</p>
<p><strong>Learn what other R folks are up to:</strong> Although I’ve changed industries, I’m still a journalist at heart. One thing I’d love to do is interview other R users about what they’re working on, either professionally or as a hobby. I foresee a rich vein of inspiration – for others as well as myself. Think of it as a podcast, but in writing.</p>
<p>Being a full-time employee and full-time grad student will definitely challenge how often I can post, but I’ll look for opportunities where available.</p>
<p>Let’s have some fun!</p>




<div id="quarto-appendix" class="default"><section class="footnotes footnotes-end-of-document"><h2 class="anchored quarto-appendix-heading">Footnotes</h2>

<ol>
<li id="fn1"><p><a href="https://albert-rapp.de/posts/13_quarto_blog_writing_guide/13_quarto_blog_writing_guide.html">Albert Rapp’s guide</a> was super helpful↩︎</p></li>
</ol>
</section></div> ]]></description>
  <category>R</category>
  <category>Quarto</category>
  <guid>https://morrisLuke.github.io//posts/not-promising-much-but-here-goes/post.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2022 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://morrisLuke.github.io///posts/not-promising-much-but-here-goes/images/hex_stickers.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
